[
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_079",
        "question": "A 42-year-old Hispanic man with no prior medical history presents with a 2-month history of a rash on his face, chest, and arms. <br>- He reports that the rash gets worse after sun exposure and he has associated joint pain. <br>- He has taken over-the-counter nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) for the joint pain and topical steroids for the rash with no symptomatic relief. <br>- Physical examination reveals erythematous patches over the malar cheeks and dorsal nose sparing the nasolabial fold and erythematous macules on the forearms and chest.",
        "option1": "Dermatitis",
        "option2": "Seborrheic dermatitis",
        "option3": "Acne rosacea",
        "option4": "Systemic lupus erythematosus",
        "correct_option": 4,
        "ai_prediction": 3,
        "ai_confidence": "64%",
        "ai_is_correct": false
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_134",
        "question": "A 65-year-old African American man presents to dermatology clinic for multiple non-painful, non-itchy brown spots on the face. <br>- He notes they started developing when he was 42 years old, and they have increased in number and size. <br>- Sometimes he tries to remove them with a needle, but they will bleed. <br>-   Physical exam reveals multiple dark, flat topped ovoid papules, and few pedunculated brown-black papules on the bilateral zygomatic cheeks.",
        "option1": "Medication induced hyperpigmentation",
        "option2": "Acne vulgaris",
        "option3": "Dermatosis papulosa nigra",
        "option4": "Melasma",
        "correct_option": 4,
        "ai_prediction": 4,
        "ai_confidence": "48%",
        "ai_is_correct": true
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_108",
        "question": "A 72-year-old woman is seen by the Dermatology consult service for a rash which has developed during a prolonged 6-week hospitalization following a hemorrhagic stroke. <br>- She is currently intubated, so history is limited, but per chart review, nurses documented the rash starting 5 days ago. <br>- She has been experiencing high fevers as well as unexplained transaminitis over the last few days. <br>- She has taken atorvastatin and pantoprazole for years, including during the hospitalization. <br>- Following the stroke, she was started on carbamazepine for seizure prophylaxis. <br>- She contracted MRSA pneumonia 2 weeks ago and has been on vancomycin since then. <br>- She has also been on cefepime and micafungin for the last 5 days given the fevers and transaminitis. <br>- Physical examination is significant for diffuse erythematous patches extending over the face, chest, back, and extremities, as well as facial edema.",
        "option1": "Drug reaction with eosinophilia and systemic symptoms",
        "option2": "Lichenoid drug eruption",
        "option3": "Morbilliform drug eruption",
        "option4": "Stevens-Johnson Syndrome",
        "correct_option": 3,
        "ai_prediction": 3,
        "ai_confidence": "74%",
        "ai_is_correct": true
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_088",
        "question": "A 50-year-old woman presents with a crop of lesions that recently appeared on her buttocks and legs. <br>- On examination, the red macules and papules range in size from a few millimeters to a few centimeters; when pressed, the lesions do not blanch or partially blanch. <br>- The patient reports joint pain over her ankles and knees, along with malaise. <br>- When questioned, she acknowledges having had a “cold” a few weeks earlier, for which her primary care provider prescribed an antibiotic. <br>- Direct immunofluorescence of the lesions reveals immunoglobulin A (IgA) deposits around the small vessels in the papillary dermis.",
        "option1": "Scurvy",
        "option2": "Maculopapular drug eruption",
        "option3": "Pigmented purpuric dermatoses",
        "option4": "IgA-mediated small vessel vasculitis",
        "correct_option": 2,
        "ai_prediction": 2,
        "ai_confidence": "80%",
        "ai_is_correct": true
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_029",
        "question": "A 72-year-old man presents to the clinic with an intensely itchy rash on his abdomen and chest that appeared 2 months prior. <br>- He denies starting any new medications prior to the onset of the eruption and any systemic symptoms. <br>- Although he traveled and stayed in hotels recently, he reports that his wife does not exhibit any similar symptoms. <br>- Physical examination reveals numerous discrete papules, crusted papules, and papulovesicles on the chest, abdomen, and mid-back. <br>- His upper and lower extremities, face, and groin are unaffected.",
        "option1": "Bullous pemphigoid",
        "option2": "Grover disease",
        "option3": "Scabies",
        "option4": "Pemphigus vulgaris",
        "correct_option": 1,
        "ai_prediction": 1,
        "ai_confidence": "71%",
        "ai_is_correct": true
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_028",
        "question": "The patient is a 13-year-old adolescent girl who presents with a 1-month history of a dark lesion on her finger. <br>- She states that the lesion does not bother her, but she came to the clinician because her mother was very concerned about the enlarging area of hyperpigmentation. <br>- The patient has no past medical history, no relevant family or social history, and is otherwise in good health. <br>- On examination, the rash appears to be a 1 x 1 cm circular patch of hyperpigmentation with overlying scale on the middle finger. <br>- During the past month, the rash has grown in size but remains asymptomatic.",
        "option1": "Acral melanoma",
        "option2": "Lentigines",
        "option3": "Acral nevi",
        "option4": "Tinea nigra",
        "correct_option": 4,
        "ai_prediction": 4,
        "ai_confidence": "76%",
        "ai_is_correct": true
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_104",
        "question": "An 8-year-old male presents with 1 week of itchy blisters on the ears. <br>- He just recently returned from spring break with his family. <br>- He denies using any particular products on the ears before the rash. <br>- He says that this has occurred yearly for the last several years, always around the same time. <br>- He denies proximal muscle weakness. <br>- He denies flaking in the scalp. <br>- Physical examination reveals tiny vesicles atop erythematous patches on the superior helices.",
        "option1": "Juvenile dermatomyositis",
        "option2": "Juvenile spring eruption",
        "option3": "Seborrheic dermatitis",
        "option4": "Allergic contact dermatitis",
        "correct_option": 2,
        "ai_prediction": 4,
        "ai_confidence": "62%",
        "ai_is_correct": false
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_023",
        "question": "The patient is a 12-year-old Hispanic girl who presents with a 6-month history of nail dystrophy involving all of her fingernails. <br>- On examination, all 10 of her fingernails exhibit longitudinal ridging, pitting, fragility, thinning, and distal notching. <br>- The patient’s mother is very concerned about the cosmesis of her daughter’s nails. <br>- The patient has no systemic symptoms. <br>- On review of systems, the patient’s mother noted that her daughter has started to develop circular patches of hair loss that appear to resolve on their own. <br>- The patient has no relevant social or family history and does not take any medications.",
        "option1": "Psoriasis",
        "option2": "Lichen planus",
        "option3": "Trachyonychia",
        "option4": "Brittle nails",
        "correct_option": 2,
        "ai_prediction": 2,
        "ai_confidence": "87%",
        "ai_is_correct": true
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_098",
        "question": "A 15-year-old white adolescent presents to the dermatology clinic with an asymptomatic rash on his upper back that has persisted for 4 months. <br>- Physical examination reveals hyperpigmented scaly papules coalescing into confluent plaques with peripheral reticulated papillomatosis. <br>- The boy is overweight but has no history of any other medical conditions.",
        "option1": "Prurigo pigmentosa",
        "option2": "Confluent and reticulated papillomatosis",
        "option3": "Amyloidosis cutis dyschromica",
        "option4": "Dowling-Degos disease",
        "correct_option": 3,
        "ai_prediction": 3,
        "ai_confidence": "67%",
        "ai_is_correct": true
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_135",
        "question": "A 5-year-old boy presents to the pediatrician office with complaints of multiple spots that began on the abdomen and spread to the arms and legs. <br>- The spots are not itchy or painful, unless he scratches them. <br>- Sometimes the skin surronding the lesion will become very red and painful, but then the lesion and redness fade. <br>- The parents report they have tried topical corticosteroids but the lesions do not go away. <br>-   Mom endorses a history of atopic dermatitis in her sister and herself. <br>-   Physical exam reveals multiple dome shaped skin colored to light pink papules with central umbilication and yellow core across the chest and back.",
        "option1": "Herpes virus infection",
        "option2": "Fibrous papule",
        "option3": "Basal cell carcinoma",
        "option4": "Molluscum contagiosum",
        "correct_option": 3,
        "ai_prediction": 3,
        "ai_confidence": "92%",
        "ai_is_correct": true
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_137",
        "question": "A 53-year-old man with a past medical history of multiple myeloma presents to dermatology clinic with multiple yellow, irritated spots under the eyes. <br>- He reports the lesions developed about four months ago, beginning as a red spot that will enlargen, bleed, and then scab over with yellow material. <br>- He denies any new facial creams, topical treatments, or new medications. <br>- He does not have any new dogs or cats. <br>-   Physical examination is remarkable for hepatosplenomegaly and on the lower eyelids bilaterally are yellow-pink thinly ulcerated plaques with yellow crust.",
        "option1": "Hidrocystoma ",
        "option2": "Necrobiosis lipoidica diabeticorum",
        "option3": "Xanthelasma",
        "option4": "Necrobiotic xanthogranuloma (NXG) ",
        "correct_option": 2,
        "ai_prediction": 2,
        "ai_confidence": "88%",
        "ai_is_correct": true
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_118",
        "question": "A 22-year-old male presents with a follicular eruption that has been present for 2 weeks. <br>- He has a history of anorexia nervosa and alcoholism. <br>- There is no identifiable preceding incident related to the eruption. <br>- He denies a history of atopy, drug use, and new medications. <br>- A review of systems shows positive findings for joint pain and bleeding gums. <br>- Physical exam reveals ecchymosis and purpuric follicular papules with corkscrew-like hair on his legs and arms.",
        "option1": "Thrombocytopenic purpura",
        "option2": "Chronic liver disease",
        "option3": "Scurvy",
        "option4": "IgA vasculitis",
        "correct_option": 4,
        "ai_prediction": 4,
        "ai_confidence": "95%",
        "ai_is_correct": true
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_129",
        "question": "A 66-year-old woman with a past medical history of hypertension and diabetes mellitus type 2 presents to clinic with a mildly painful, pruritic peeling skin on the chest and back that began 4 weeks ago. <br>- She denies any new medications, new topical creams or lotions, or laundry detergents. <br>- She has been applying vaseline to the spots. <br>- She also thinks she may have a similar spot on the scalp. <br>- She denies any similar spots in the mouth, and denies forming any blisters on the skin. <br>-   Physical exam demonstrates multiple thinly eroded pink-red oval plaques on the chest, scalp, back with yellow brown corn-flake like scale. <br>- Ocular and oral mucosa are normal.",
        "option1": "Pemphigus foliaceous",
        "option2": "Bullous arthropod assault",
        "option3": "Pemphigus vulgaris",
        "option4": "Bullous pemphigoid",
        "correct_option": 2,
        "ai_prediction": 2,
        "ai_confidence": "75%",
        "ai_is_correct": true
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_096",
        "question": "A 53-year-old man presents to the clinic with ulcerated, scarred, and hypertrophic plaques on both lower extremities. <br>- He is a refugee from Sudan who arrived in the United States a month earlier. <br>- He reports that the lesions started as red bumps that slowly expanded and developed a raised border. <br>- Several of his family members in Sudan have had similar lesions in the past, and he is concerned that he may have developed the same condition.",
        "option1": "Leishmaniasis",
        "option2": "Cutaneous anthrax",
        "option3": "Leprosy",
        "option4": "Ulceroglandular tularemia",
        "correct_option": 1,
        "ai_prediction": 4,
        "ai_confidence": "79%",
        "ai_is_correct": false
    },
    {
        "qid": "craftmd_050",
        "question": "A healthy 15-year-old girl presents with a solitary, asymptomatic lesion on her back. <br>- The lesion has been present since birth but has enlarged over the past 2 years. <br>- She denies association with previous trauma and irritation. <br>- Examination reveals multiple, comedo-like openings filled with dark lamellate keratinocyte plugs grouped in a linear distribution over a slightly hypotrophic area of 3 cm by 7 cm. <br>- Dermoscopy revealed numerous circular and barrel-shaped homogenous areas in dark-brown shades with remarkable keratin plugs.",
        "option1": "Segmental acne",
        "option2": "Familial dyskeratotic comedones",
        "option3": "Trichofolliculoma",
        "option4": "Nevus comedonicus",
        "correct_option": 1,
        "ai_prediction": 1,
        "ai_confidence": "92%",
        "ai_is_correct": true
    }
]